E-mail: gregor.panic@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/gregorpanic/

Web: https://glhfgreg.github.io/

GREGOR PANIČ

GAME DESIGNER

PROFILE

Experienced game designer with a technical background. I turn high-level concepts into practical designs that can be prototyped and evaluated. I have the technical knowledge to communicate between creative and engineering to solve challenges. I'm comfortable being hands-on - implementing designs in various engines and tools. I have a broad design skill set and experience, from gameplay systems, player controllers, levels, to game AI.

EXPERIENCE

Embark Studios, Malmö, Sweden - Technical Designer, Track Owner

JUNE 2022 - PRESENT

- Worked on wim, a social, multiplayer, creative sandbox.
- Lead an interdisciplinary team with a focus on NPCs and game AI.
- Worked closely with the creative lead to define the vision for NPCs, setting high-level goals, scope and roadmap from prototype to final implementation.
- Provided design feedback to make NPCs more meaningful and ensure cohesion with the project vision.
- Facilitated communication with other teams to help the project stay focused and lead brainstorming and playtest sessions.
- Co-designed a systemic, living world with emergent events.
- Designed an AI director system that provides challenges for players.
- Designed multiple player tools for manipulating the world.
- Implemented several AI behaviors using Rust within a custom engine.

Frictional Games, Malmö, Sweden - Gameplay programmer & designer

SEPTEMBER 2016 - JUNE 2022

- Worked on Amnesia: Rebirth, an atmospheric first-person horror game.
- Responsible for bringing multiple levels from concept to shippable quality.
- Coordinated art, tech and sound to achieve the desired vision for a level.
- Designed and implemented 6 main levels, 2 main enemies, the fear system (central mechanic) and other gameplay systems.
- Designed and developed a system for aligning player and enemy npc animations - used for when the player is caught by enemies.
- Worked on the player controller, including implementing cutscene animations, environment interactions and interactions between players and enemies.

- Integrated Tobii eye tracking for <u>SOMA</u> and developed eye tracking features for the player controller.
- Programming was done in AngelScript and C++ in a custom engine.

Self-employed, Maribor, Slovenia — Game developer

SEPTEMBER 2013 - SEPTEMBER 2016

- Made <u>Welkin Road</u>, a first-person parkour game with grappling hooks.
- Solo project where I did art, game design, level design and programming.
- Developed a custom player controller with parkour mechanics such as wall running, wall jumping, swinging with grappling hooks, sliding, crouching, vaulting and climbing.
- Made in Unity using C#.

TOOLS

C#, AngelScript, C++, Miro, Git, SVN, Unreal Blueprints, Unity, Godot, Blender, HPL Engine, Rust, JIRA, Trello, GitHub.

EDUCATION

University of Maribor, Slovenia - MS in Computer Science

2012 - 2015, Maribor, Slovenia

University of Maribor, Slovenia — BS in Computer Science

2009 - 2012, Maribor, Slovenia

SMALLER PROJECTS

OMG it's Mr.MANO! - 2024

https://davidpdrsn.itch.io/mano

Experimental game where you resize your hand to give the best high fives. Entry for GMTK 2024 game jam. Worked on design and programming as part of a team. Made in Godot.

Stagehand - 2024

https://glhfgreg.itch.io/stagehand

You play the lead role in an 80s sit-com, trying to use slapstick humor to make the audience laugh. Entry for Global Game Jam 2024. Worked on design and programming as part of a team. Made in Unreal.

Almighty Dice - 2022

https://measuring.itch.io/almighty-dice

A 1v1 competitive dice throwing game. Entry for GMTK 2022. Worked on design and programming as part of a duo. Made in Unreal.